Thomas Ingram

Apex, NC 27502 rg+hireme@ravinggenius.com m: 919 449.6305

Professional Summary

- · Self-taught programmer with strong desire to learn
- Webmaster for many sites (some built from scratch and some CMS-based)
- · Strong sense of object-oriented programming
- MVC (Rails, Sinatra, Merb, ASP.NET MVC, others)
- GNU|Linux evangelist and Open Source advocate
- Well-developed analytical skills
- Worked with large datasets (1.5M to 2M records)
- · Attend trade meetings and conferences regularly
- Configured systems and networks professionally and personally
- · Technical advisor to several people

Technical Summary

Languages: HTML (4, 5), CSS (2, 2.1, 3), Ruby (1.8, 1.9), JavaScript | JSON, PHP (4, 5), C# (2, 3), VB (2, 3), ASP.NET (2, 3, 3.5), XML, ColdFusion, Flex | AS3, VBA

Databases: SQLite, MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB

Code Samples: http://github.com/ravinggenius

Other: git, SVN, REST, VIM, text editor, Regular Expressions, Visual Studio (2005, 2008), Pair Programming, Drupal (4.7, 5, 6), Agile, TDD, SharePoint 2007, Joomla! (1.1, 1.5)

Future Interests: Server-side JavaScript, LISP, C++, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, Graphic Design, Java (maybe), The Next Big Thing

Professional Experience

RoleModel Software; Independent Contractor; Holly Springs, NC; 04/2010 - present

- Helped build a digital kiosk for distributing Bibles and Bible-related material to third-world countries Ruby, Rails, HAML/SASS, JavaScript, PostgreSQL
- Helped build an internal tool for Procter & Gamble Ruby, Rails, HAML/SASS, JavaScript, PostgreSQL

яandomByDesign; Freelancer | Owner; Apex, NC; 03/2008 - present

- Created a church CMS-backed website for a friend Drupal, PHP, MySQL
- · Hand-crafted several websites for friends and family Ruby, Sinatra, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

CISYS | Life Sciences; Web Developer; N Raleigh, NC; 10/2007 - 03/2010

- Built a SharePoint-backed IRB system from scratch with custom secure login C#, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
 - Built a flexible **ORM** for interacting with SharePoint's database (inspired by **Ruby**'s **DataMapper**)
 - Created many helper classes, including an HTML-generation library
- Created several websites, primarily using ASP.NET technologies, including CISYS'. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, C#, VB.NET, PHP
- Advocated improved development methodologies, such as test-driven development
- · Contracted with partner/vendor, Presentation Strategies
 - Supported existing reporting projects MSSQL, XML, VBA
 - Updated and maintained some websites PHP, HTML, CSS, MSSQL, MySQL

Sir Speedy Cary; Mail Room Supervisor | Web Developer; Cary, NC; 09/2005 - 10/2007

- · Built an online ordering system for our largest client to replace the old one PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL
- · Address and prepare letters and postcards for bulk mail
- · Cut paper, run deliveries, collate, hole punch and make computer recommendations

Education

Sandhills Community College; Pinehurst, NC; 2001 spring

- · Accrued some basic credits
- · Left after a semester because of finances

Pensacola Christian College; Pensacola, FL; 2000 spring

- Computer Science major
- · Left after a semester because of stringent rules

Calvary Christian School; Southern Pines, NC; 1995 - 1999

· Chose electives that focused on Math, Physics and Logic

Certifications

- Computer Troubleshooting; Wake Technical Community College; 2006
- MySQL; Wake Technical Community College; 2005